<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>japan on it&#39;s my life</title>
    <link>/tags/japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in japan on it&#39;s my life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 08:02:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JapShake</title>
      <link>/2008/03/10/japshake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 08:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/03/10/japshake/</guid>
      <description>I have tried sushi, sake, karaoke, teriyaki and all the well-known Japanese stuff. I was still missing something, but I couldn’t do anything to arrange it. When I thought that I was coming back to Nederland, it came: my first earthquake.
Indeed it is not the first one. Ten years ago I was in the States and there was an earthquake during the night. I couldn’t notice. Indeed I’m a deep sleeper so the room could be on fire and I wouldn’t notice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telephone in the train</title>
      <link>/2008/03/02/telephone-in-the-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 02:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/03/02/telephone-in-the-train/</guid>
      <description>You might think that there is a lot of people sending and receiving phone calls in the metro or the train because Japanese people love their mobiles so much&amp;hellip; No.
It was the case some years ago, when the mobile fever started. The situation was so bad that the government passed new laws and calling is forbidden in trains. Even further, the telephone must be set on manner mode (silence or vibrating).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number 2</title>
      <link>/2008/03/01/number-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/03/01/number-2/</guid>
      <description>What you see in the photo is not an advance remote controller for a Home Cinema device but the toilet control. There are three kind of toilets in this country, the plain European one, the traditional Japanese (mainly a hole in the ground) and the hi-tech version of the European.
The latest has some of this functions:
 * A heating system integrated in the seat. * A shower-like function to clean your thing after the unloading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buzzword</title>
      <link>/2008/02/28/buzzword/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 15:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/28/buzzword/</guid>
      <description>During the last three weeks I have attended many presentations. Some of them are full of buzz-words and I want to summarize them in a new definition for Smart Surroundings:
A new innovative high-speed seamless customised semantic context-aware user-centric face/pattern/image/emotion-recognition-capable high-definition multimedia ubiquitous set of applications, and services developed and implemented using state-of-the-art frameworks, middleware, next generation sensors, RFID, Near Field Communications, optical devices and wireless technology. Is this buzzword-compliant enough?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication issues</title>
      <link>/2008/02/27/communication-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 14:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/27/communication-issues/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people warned me beforehand about the level of English spoken in Japan. It is not as bad as in my home country, but still. Ordering food in the restaurant is an adventure and asking a price in a shop can be a challenge.
Anyway, the new generations seems to be more prepared, there is awareness about the problem and Erik sent me the link to the solution proposed in the Japanese TV, combining fitness and language, body and soul in one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five minutes</title>
      <link>/2008/02/26/five-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 13:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/26/five-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Time goes fast around this corner of the world and I wanted to mention some small thingies about our trip to Japan:
 * The temperature in Japanes offices is terrible. In most places we have seen the airco working at 25 degrees, and people are working happily while we sweat our suits. * It is impossible to find a trash can. For whatever reason it takes minutes to find one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dutch Factor</title>
      <link>/2008/02/24/the-dutch-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 01:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/24/the-dutch-factor/</guid>
      <description>We arrived at the station at 17:30 and the panels were showing that trains were scheduled at 16:06 and 16:30. Time travel? No&amp;hellip; the Dutch Factor. The Shinkansen, the worldwide famous bullet train was once again delayed, as if it was ruled by the NS, and that could be due to the presence of Dutch travelers.
After some communication attemps we found out that there were some strong winds and the Shinkansen is not supposed to take off, so the trains were grounded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say it with a smile</title>
      <link>/2008/02/21/say-it-with-a-smile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 13:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/21/say-it-with-a-smile/</guid>
      <description>I have see all kind of presentations around here. I might say that presentations in big companies are mostly really good. Today we went to NTT DoCoMo and the movies there where amazing. On the other hand, the first presentation, in another company, was extremely boring, with a guy telling us how wonderful his campus is, how many companies are there, in which buildings, and the specific details of the 20 divisions of his company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A-Day in Hiroshima</title>
      <link>/2008/02/17/a-day-in-hiroshima/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/17/a-day-in-hiroshima/</guid>
      <description>People don&amp;rsquo;t work usually here on Sundays, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any company visit on the program. We started the day with a nice buffet breakfast, including some unhealthy but delicious meat stuff.
Later we took the once more delayed Shinkansen to the city of Hiroshima. For those who do not watch &amp;ldquo;Who wants to be a millionaire&amp;rdquo;, Hiroshima is the first city that suffered the devastating effects of the American atomic bomb during World War II.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kyoto protocol</title>
      <link>/2008/02/16/the-kyoto-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 06:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/16/the-kyoto-protocol/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we spent the night in a budhist temple. I was expecting something more classic, but instead it was more IKEA-style. If I summarize my experience in one word it would be &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo;. The thing was freaking cold. Moreover we had to walk around without shoes and the thing sucks. For the last two days I have barely used shoes!
Anyway, now I understand what all this Kyoto protocol is about: since there is a global warming, let&amp;rsquo;s switch us the heating!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The white things</title>
      <link>/2008/02/16/the-white-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 06:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/16/the-white-things/</guid>
      <description>Apart from the background of the flag there are more white things I noticed in Japan.
First one is the white mask, similar to those that the dentists use, that some people use in public spaces such as metro, bus and so on.
What are those things for? It is no more no less than a sign of respect for the healthy ones: they are sick and they don&amp;rsquo;t want to spread their sickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning the food</title>
      <link>/2008/02/12/returning-the-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 14:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/12/returning-the-food/</guid>
      <description>Lately we have been eating really a lot: sushi, teri-yake and even hamburguers for breakfast. Together with the lack of sleep and the jet-lag, the mix is not really good.
We were in the bus to a company and Ronald, from the organizing committee (OC) suddenly looked like a balloon-fish. He started to puke and half of the bus was covered with his food left-overs. I could escape from the flood literally for centimeters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First impressions</title>
      <link>/2008/02/10/first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 15:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/10/first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>There are two things that so far have impressed me a lot. First of all, I really can&amp;rsquo;t understand the signs, excepting those for the toilets.
Second impression: Japanese people are really nice. Two examples: the cabin crew in the airplane was telling me &amp;ldquo;Sorry for the delay in bringing the food&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Thank you very much, we are proud of having you here&amp;rdquo; and so on. We went to a restaurant for dinner and even if we were supposed to use the touch-screen automated waiter service a waiter came to us to try to explain the menu in her poor English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3...2...1...</title>
      <link>/2008/02/08/321/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 13:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/08/321/</guid>
      <description>In a few minutes I will leave to Rotterdam and tomorrow I will fly to Japan. Currently I am doing a list in my mind of the things I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t forget.
Yesterday we went to a traditional Japanese restaurant in Borne. I must say that the food was delicious. We had a cook cooking just in front of us and the process was quite impressive. I guess that Japanese are more similar in that sense to Spanish people than for Dutch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 days... and counting.</title>
      <link>/2008/01/31/8-days-and-counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 20:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/31/8-days-and-counting/</guid>
      <description>It feels like it was yesterday when I told Jorrit: &amp;ldquo;Hey, it seems that some guys are going to Japan&amp;rdquo;. In a couple of days we were in an office asking for information. Today we finished all the previous work, after all it is a study trip, and now it is time to pack the stuff and go.
I might say I am quite excited. I have learnt that Japan is a totally different country, the cultural shock is going to be 100 times bigger than when I moved to the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>